https://geoinformatics.com/privacy-cookies/

for Surveying, Mapping & GIS
Who we areCMedia BV publishes a range of ebooks, magazines, newsletters and websites for the Geo- and CAD-community (the “content”).To support the publication of the content, we may gather and process your personal information. We will do this in accordance with this Privacy Notice (‘notice’) and in compliance with the relevant data protection regulations and laws. This notice provides you with information regarding your rights and our obligations and explains how, why and when we process your personal information. References in this notice, to “website” or “websites” are to the specific CMedia website which links to this notice.CMedia’s registered office is at Constructieweg 19 in Emmeloord and we are a registered company in the Netherlands.Your PrivacyWe are committed to ensuring the security and protection of the personal information we process. We will make every reasonable effort to protect your privacy by adopting a high level of website security and adhering to company policies on how we store and use personal information.This notice relates to our use of the personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us, via the online services we make available to you, by phone, email, in letters and other correspondence and in person. It has been created to help you understand our views and practices regarding your personal information.We recommend that you read this notice prior to using our websites, product and services. If we change this notice we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the website, so that you will be aware of the personal information we collect and how we will use it. If you use this website or our products and services, or access our content on this website, after any such change has been made, you will be deemed to have read and accepted the change.Personal Information we may collect from youThe personal information we collect about you, or that you provide to us, will be dependent on your relationship with us, the services we provide to you, the way in which you choose to interact with us and your level of engagement with us.Personal Information you give usYou may give us personal information when you fill in forms on our websites or when you correspond with us by phone, email, in writing or otherwise. The types of personal information we may collect about you include but are not limited to:Your name and contact information including your email address;Your institutional affiliation and level of education;Your employer or the organisation that you represent;Demographic information such as your research interests;Payment information; andOpinions or other information you provide when you complete surveys, enter competitions or respond to questions from us.Personal Information we collect about youWhen you visit our websites, we may collect the following information automatically:technical information, including the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, your geographic location, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; andinformation about your visit, including the source of your visit, the full click path, mouse movement through our websites (including date and time); services you viewed, searches made on our websites, page response times, download errors and length of visits to certain pages.Personal Information we collect at receipt and opening of emailsWhen you open an email sent by us, we may collect the following personal information automatically:technical information, including; your geographic location, browser type and version, device type and operating system and platform; andinformation about your email consumption, including the full click path from within and on to our sites (including date and time), whether the email was delivered, shared, unsubscribed from, opened, deleted or forwarded.Personal Information from third partiesFrom time to time, and as permitted by applicable law(s), we may collect personal information about you from other third-party sources, including publicly available data sources and your employer or university/school. This personal information may be used to update and enhance any existing personal information that we currently hold.How we use your personal informationDepending on your relationship with us, we may process your personal information in the following ways:To provide our products and services to you or to facilitate the provision of products, services and content to your employer, university or institution;To respond to your requests and enquiries;To invite you to participate in research studies, to submit work for our content or to attend live events or webinars;To invite you to peer review and to manage the peer review process;To publish your name, institution, country, ORCID ID, and in some cases your email address alongside your work;In the course of arranging a press release;Administering and managing our relationships with individuals who sit on our Editorial Advisory Boards;To process payments from you (including, but not limited to, article publication charges, subscriptions or payments for any products or services that you choose to purchase from us);To process payments to you (including, but not limited to, refunds or reimbursements, or payments to you for services provided to us);To provide access to restricted parts of our websites;To produce statistics about the usage levels of our websites to allow us to understand what we are doing well and where we can improve the online services we offer, as well as other internal purposes, such as website and system administration or internal audits and reviews. We may share aggregated statistics to third parties that we work with, but these statistics will not include information which will allow you to be identified; andTo comply with applicable law(s) (for example, to comply with a court order) or to carry out professional ethics/conduct investigations.We will process your personal information for the purposes identified above on the following bases:Our legitimate interests, which include, but are not limited to, processing your personal information for the purposes of providing and enhancing the provision of our products, services and information;Where processing is necessary to perform our contract with you or to take steps before entering into a contract with you;As necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our contractual agreements; andWhere you have consented to our use of your personal information for a specified purpose. Where this is the case, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.Our use of your personal information for Marketing activitiesMarketing by Post: Occasionally we will send you marketing information by post where we have decided that it is beneficial to you as a customer and in our interests. Such information will be non-intrusive and is processed on the grounds of legitimate interests.Marketing by Email: Where you have consented to us sending you email updates about our content including, but not limited to, our online content, industry news and updates, events and webinars, competitions and surveys, you are free to withdraw this consent at any time. If you have provided information about your interest areas, or have purchased or used our products and/or services, we may use this information to tailor the content of our emails to you. We will not send you marketing emails if you have opted out of receiving them. Any marketing emails we send you will include an unsubscribe link at the end of the email.If you would like to stop receiving marketing emails from us, you can let us know by:Clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any promotional emails you receive from us;Emailing us (please ensure you tell us if you would like to opt out from all email marketing communications or just a particular update; and/orPhoning us on +31 (0) 527619000  (Mon-Fri 9am-5pm BST/GMT).How long we will retain your personal informationWe may retain certain records for other legitimate reasons (including after your relationship with us has ended), for example to maintain records of articles published in our content, to resolve any potential disputes and to comply with reporting and retention obligations.Who we share your personal information withWe will never sell, trade or rent your personal information to others. However, we may share your personal information with selected third-parties. We require that our third-party service providers only use your personal information as necessary to provide the requested services. It is likely that the identity and categories of the third-party service providers with whom we share your personal information will change during the life of your relationship with us. Depending on that relationship, and your use of our websites, it is anticipated that your personal information will be disclosed to the following categories of third-party service providers who perform functions on our behalf.Where we store your personal informationBy providing us with your personal information, you acknowledge that it may be transferred to, stored at and processed at a destination inside or outside the European Economic Area by us, our affiliates and/or other third parties. Please do not submit any personal information to us if you do not wish for it to be transferred internationally.Your RightsYou have the right to access any personal information that we process about you and to request information about: –What personal information we hold about youThe purposes of the processingThe categories of personal information concernedThe recipients to whom the personal information has/will be disclosedHow long we intend to store your personal information for; andIf we did not collect the personal information directly from you, information about the source.Correcting or updating the personal information we hold about youIf you believe that we hold any incomplete or inaccurate information about you, you have the right to ask us to correct and/or complete it and we will strive to correct it as quickly as possible; unless there is a valid reason for not doing so, at which point you will be notified. You can inform us of updates or corrections required to your personal information using personalisation options of the website.CookiesWhat are Cookies?This website may place small text files, called cookies, on your computer to distinguish you from other users of this website. These cookies monitor how you use this website so that IOPP can make improvements, and are also used to give you the best user experience (for example by remembering your login details so that you do not have to enter them each time). Some cookies may also be placed by third parties, for example Facebook and Google, if you use their services via this website, to monitor how you use their services and to target relevant advertising to you when you visit other websites on which they advertise.In most cases, cookies do not contain personally identifiable information.What cookies may be placed?This website may use the following types of cookies:Strictly necessary cookies (Type 1): these cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around this website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of this website. Without these cookies, certain services you have asked for cannot be provided.Analytical/performance cookies (Type 2): these cookies allow IOPP to recognise and count the number of visits to this website and to see how visitors move around this website when they are using it, so that we can improve how this website works. These cookies do not collect personally identifiable information.Functionality cookies (Type 3): these cookies remember choices you make to improve your experience on this website; for example, your user name, language or region.Targeting cookies (Type 4): these cookies are placed by third parties to collect information about your browsing habits when you elect to use their services, in order to make advertising relevant to you and your interests.CMedia BV is not responsible for the use of cookies by third parties, and users are encouraged to read the privacy statements of those third party service providers before using their services.How do I opt-out of cookies?Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org. You should note that deleting certain cookies may prevent you from accessing certain parts of this website and/or may affect your user experience.Lodging A ComplaintWe will process your personal information in accordance with this notice and in accordance with the relevant data protection laws. If, however, you wish to raise a complaint regarding the processing of your personal information, or are unsatisfied with how we have handled your personal information, you have the right to lodge a complaint:CMedia BV, Constructieweg 19, 8305 AA, Emmeloord, The NetherlandsTelephone: +31 (0) 527 619 000Email: info@cmedia.nl
CMedia is publisher of GeoInformatics and  BIGnieuws Magazine
By continuing to browse the site you are agreeing to our use of cookies. I Understand
Scroll to Top
